<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Efficiency on GoodyHao's Blog</title><link>https://gooddayday.github.io/en/categories/efficiency/</link><description>Recent content in Efficiency on GoodyHao's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>865700600@qq.com (GoodyHao)</managingEditor><webMaster>865700600@qq.com (GoodyHao)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 22:29:56 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gooddayday.github.io/en/categories/efficiency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[Github] 4. Value-Checker-Java: Customizable AOP Validation Framework</title><link>https://gooddayday.github.io/en/2025/09/github-4.-value-checker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 23:27:17 +0800</pubDate><author>865700600@qq.com (GoodyHao)</author><guid>https://gooddayday.github.io/en/2025/09/github-4.-value-checker/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Value-Checker-Java is essentially a &lt;strong&gt;customizable AOP pointcut framework&lt;/strong&gt;. It allows developers to insert custom validation logic before method execution, and this validation logic can be arbitrarily complex business rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if it merely provides an AOP pointcut, that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be very meaningful. &lt;strong&gt;The core value of Value-Checker-Java lies in its thread-safe context management mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;. Without this context management, data queried in the first validator cannot be used in subsequent validators, forcing each validator to re-query data, which defeats the purpose of validation chains.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>[Github] 3. Basic-Check: Validation Framework</title><link>https://gooddayday.github.io/en/2025/09/github-3.-basic-check/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 22:27:17 +0800</pubDate><author>865700600@qq.com (GoodyHao)</author><guid>https://gooddayday.github.io/en/2025/09/github-3.-basic-check/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parameter validation is a common and crucial requirement in daily Java development. Traditional parameter validation typically requires writing extensive if-else conditional code in each method, which is not only redundant and tedious but also prone to omissions. Basic-Check-Java was born to solve this pain point as a lightweight parameter validation framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article will provide an in-depth introduction to Basic-Check-Java&amp;rsquo;s design philosophy, core features, and practical applications, helping developers quickly master this practical tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>